I woke up this morning to a war going on in Gaza in Southern Israel and I want to give
this conflict background before I head into work.
I'm in Spartanburg, South Carolina right now on a consulting job but I have a few minutes
for I have to be on site and keep in mind that all I have is a laptop right now and a lot
of my tools and large monitors aren't with me.
The tough thing is that I have a number of Israeli viewers and I also have a number of
Palestinian viewers who by the way think it's hilarious when I speak Arabic with my Egyptian accent.
What I'd really like is for everybody just kind of go home and live in peace but that doesn't
seem to be in the cards right now.
So here's what I think is going on and then I want to get into some of the background on the
Israel, Palestinian conflict.
On October 7th, Palestinian forces launched thousands of rockets into Israel.
They also conducted raids into Southern Israel over land, sea and believe you're not air.
That's right, Palestinian forces launched uh, paragliders into Israel.
So that's certainly one way of doing infiltration.
Now from what I understand these Palestinian forces are focused on the city of Ash-Klaun
where they have gone door-to-door attacking and in some cases kidnapping civilians.
So here's a background.
Jews, Arabs, and Christians, live together and mostly peaceful coexistence in Palestine for
hundreds of years under the rule of the Ottoman Turks.
World War I broke out in 1914.
The Turks were on Germany's side. Britain decided to open up a southern front by capturing the
cyanide peninsula and taking Palestine from the Turks.
Now there is no more dangerous predator in the desert than a better one and is rifle.
So Britain recruited Arab leaders to their side to fight against the Turks by promise and
them Palestine when they won.
Britain also recruited several petions made up of local Jews living in Palestine with the promise
that if they helped defeat the Turks, the Jews would get their own homeland.
This was very appealing to a Jewish movement called Zionism, which basically advocated for a Jewish
homeland. Zion, by the way, is the name for a hill in Jerusalem and sometimes it's used
colloquially in the Bible for Jerusalem. So Britain essentially promised the same piece of land
to the Arabs and the Jews and while this may seem crazy and hindsight, it raised the troops that
Britain needed to open up the southern front against Turkey.
Britain eventually received a mandate from the League of Nations to administer Palestine.
In 1947 the United Nations proposed a partition plan for Palestine which recommended the establishment
of separate Jewish and Arab states with Jerusalem under international administration.
This plan was accepted by Jewish leadership but it was rejected by the Arab states and Palestinian
Arab leaders. The partition plan was never fully implemented. Israel declared independence
in May of 1948, neighbouring Arab states invaded Israel immediately, leading to the 1948 Arab
Israeli war. Israel calls it the war of independence. The Arabs call it Anakhba, the catastrophe.
Even though Israel was poorly equipped and trained, they somehow won against five nations,
Egypt, Iraq, Syria, Jordan and Lebanon. Jewish militias then expelled over 700,000 Palestinians
from their homes. The state of Israel grew beyond the original borders set by the United Nations.
Many Palestinians ended up in a thin strip of land called Gaza or this landlocked area called
West Bank or Lebanon. And before you think about how barbaric it was for Israel to eject these people,
I want you to look at your neighbor. The only reason that you are alive today is thousands of
years ago someone from your tribe wiped out someone from a competing tribe. You have the luxury
of being able to clutch your pearls at Israel's actions because your tribe won the war before social
media. I mean I'm sure everybody in Florida feels horrible about what Andrew Jackson did to the
seminal nation but then they're like, you know, it is nice we don't have to shovel snow.
So that's the root of the conflict. You have a country that just wants to write to exist,
putting itself against a nation of refugees that don't feel like they got what they were promised.
And that's the general background. What's going on right now is that Israel is activating its
service and life is going to get pretty hard for the Palestinians in the next few days. I strongly
suggest that you join my Substack, Ryan MacBeth.substack.com. It's free because I'm probably not going
to be able to show you sort of kind of footage on YouTube and that's really going to make it hard
for me to perform analysis. I got to get to my consulting gig, I'll be monitoring the situation
as best I can. Thank you guys for watching.